Seph Burgweger

Seph.Burgweger@gmail.com · 203-962-4661

SUMMARY

Denison University graduate with a strong interest in pursuing a career in the craft beer industry. Have been homebrewing for several years. AmeriCorps service responsibilities included: scheduling and conducting home energy audits and weatherizations; leading teams of volunteers; raising awareness of energy efficiency and environmental issues. Experience in developing customer relationships. Able to provide reliable, diligent, and organized service as a team member or as a team leader. Able to learn new things, to solve problems, and to help where needed.

EXPERIENCE

Host

OLD GREENWICH SOCIAL CLUB

Old Greenwich, CT

t

November 2015-Present
Greet and interact with customers to ensure a positive dining experience. Make beverage recommendations. Manage reservations

and seating arrangements.

FREELANCE Cos Cob, CT

August 2012-Present

• Engage in a part-time enterprise providing home and personal services such as landscape management, home improvement.

Optimized shelf space for Castle Hill Imports warehouse; assembled shelves; setup and tore-down trade show booth.

JILL OBERLANDER CAMPAIGN

Greenwich, CT

Campaign Aide

October 2014-November 2014

Led volunteers in campaign activities and assisted with campaign mailings to voters.

GREEN IOWA AMERICORPS

Cedar Rapids, IA

Logistics Coordinator

October 2011-August 2012

- Scheduled and conducted over 55 home energy audits for clients. Set up equipment to collect data on the building air leakage rate for home energy audits and used the data collected during the weatherization phase to make energy efficiency improvements.
- Led teams of volunteers and employees to execute over 60 home weatherizations helping to conserve energy for elderly, low income, disabled or military veteran families.
- Partnered with Matthew 25, a non-profit neighborhood revitalization organization, to weatherize rehabilitated homes damaged by flood. Helped plan and plant a rain garden for Matthew 25 to demonstrate alternative method of storm water management.
- Compiled and submitted program reports focused on home energy audits, weatherizations, education events, outreach events, and volunteer involvement for site and program sponsors, which updated Green Iowa funders on our site's accomplishments.
- Organized recycling efforts at the Cedar Rapids Downtown Farmers Market and Irish District Music & Arts Festival. Recruited and trained volunteers to assist with recycling at the events.
- Taught energy efficiency & environmental topics. Programs included educating 100 6th graders about water conservation and hazardous waste for the county landfill.

AMERICORPS NATIONAL CIVILIAN COMMUNITY CORPS

Vinton, IA

Corps Member

May 2010-February 2011

- Improved and increased awareness of recycling for the City of Sioux Falls, SD by organizing and executing an Eco-camp for 20 participants (k-5) as well as conducting trash hauler inspections and trash audits at city parks to quantify the percentage of recyclables disposed of in the landfill.
- Restored grassland prairies with the Indiana Nature Conservancy to achieve their mission of land conservation. Operated and maintained chainsaws and brush cutters. Applied herbicide to invasive and unwanted plant species.
- Organized resources, including building materials and tools, for Habitat for Humanity Greater Des Moines & Cedar Valley. Assisted Des Moines affiliate during 2010 Blitz Build to complete 10 homes in 20 days. Assisted Cedar Rapids affiliate with Brush of Kindness program to beautify low income neighborhoods. Followed safe lead paint removal practices.
- Completed surveys for the Wapello County, IA Long Term Disaster Relief Committee. Received needs assessment survey training from a FEMA representative. Scheduled meetings and interviewed flood recovery victims and assessed further needs.
- Prepared project portfolios highlighting project details & accomplishments for program administrators.
- Served as a team Media Representative writing press releases for projects and contacting news outlets for press coverage.

GREENWICH LAND TRUST

Cos Cob, CT

Intern

Fall 2008-Spring 2009

- Organized and created over 100 property files for use by Land Stewardship Volunteers. Utilized ArcGIS to create maps of conservation properties owned for the property files. Assisted the Environmental Director with property inspections & data entry.
- Helped with the setup, execution, and cleanup of over four GO Wild! events, an annual fundraiser.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Volunteer: Greenwich Land Trust (2012-present), Presidential Volunteer Service Award (2011)

EDUCATION

DENISON UNIVERSITY Bachelor of Arts, Geoscience

Granville, OH

May 2008

Involvement: Lambda Chi Alpha – Secretary, Assistant House Manager & Member; Water Polo Club – President, Coach & Member, LeaderShape – 6-day leadership course designed to give its participants tools to be better leaders